[
    {
        "front": "event class",
        "back": "For a sample space $S$ and a probability measure $P,$ the event class, denoted by $\\mathcal{F}$ is a collection of all subsets of $S$ to which we will assign probability (i.e., for which $P$ will be defined). The sets in $\\mathcal{F}$ are called events."
    },
    {
        "front": "power set",
        "back": "For a set $S$ with finite cardinality, $|S|=N < \\infty$, the power set is the set of all possible subsets. We will use the notation $2^S$ to denote the power set."
    },
    {
        "front": "probability measure",
        "back": "The probability measure, $P$, is a real-valued set function that maps every element of the event class to the real line."
    },
    {
        "front": "composite experiment",
        "back": "A composite experiment is any experiment that consists of multiple sub-experiments."
    },
    {
        "front": "trial (compound experiments)",
        "back": "A trial in a compound experiment is one of the sub-experiments that make up the composite experiment."
    },
    {
        "front": "repeated experiment",
        "back": "A repeated experiment is a compound experiment in which the trials are identical and independent of each other."
    },
    {
        "front": "statistical regularity",
        "back": "An experiment has statistical regularity if under repeated experiments, the relative frequencies converge (in some sense) to some fixed values. "
    },
    {
        "front": "outcome (of a random experiment)",
        "back": "An outcome of a random experiment is a result of the experiment that cannot be further decomposed."
    },
    {
        "front": "sample space",
        "back": "The sample space of a random experiment is the set of all possible outcomes."
    },
    {
        "front": "event",
        "back": "An event is a set of outcomes. The event occurs if the result of the experiment is any of the outcomes in the set. "
    },
    {
        "front": "fair (random experiment)",
        "back": "An experiment is said to be fair if every outcome is equally likely."
    },
    {
        "front": "combinatorics",
        "back": "*Combinatorics* is the mathematics of counting. "
    },
    {
        "front": "cartesian product",
        "back": "The _cartesian product_ of two sets $A$ and $B$ is denoted $A \\times B$ and is defined by \n\n$$A \\times B = \\{ (a,b) | a \\in A \\mbox{ and } b \\in B\\}.\n$$\nThat is, it is the set of all two-tuples with the first element from set $A$ and the second element from set $B$."
    },
    {
        "front": "permutation:",
        "back": "A *permutation* is an ordering (or reordering) of a set of objects."
    }
]
